Aquib Vadsaria

Software Developer

SUMMARY

Almost 7 years of experience out of which working as a web developer from past 3 years, full stack developer for 2 years and system engineer for 2 years.

Proficient in Front end technologies majorly around HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript (React.js, Redux, Rx.js).

Career objective and focus is to become a Software Architect while advocating clean code, modern software practices and keep on actively learning new technologies and frameworks.

EXPERIENCE

J.P. Morgan Chase - Application Developer

NOVEMBER 2016 - PRESENT

- Working as a Senior Front End Developer for FX Trading platform, developing new trading applications and rewriting legacy FLEX trading platform into HTML5.
- Collaborate with global team and contribute through PR process.
- Delivered knowledge transfer session about React and JS ecosystem to Flex Developers.
- Developed internal React component library to be used by various other banking applications.
- Optimized the app build process from 10 mins to 4 mins by running grunt tasks parallel.

Technology stack: React, Redux, Rx.js, ES6, Typescript, GIT, JIRA, Node.js, Webpack, Rollup, Jest, Enzyme, CSS3, HTML5, Grunt, Jasmine.

Built.io - Web Developer

AUGUST 2015 - OCT 2016

- Worked on **Built.io Flow** web application which is a service orchestration tool for creating complex workflows.
- Major development contribution was to reduce initial loading time from 2 mins to 45 seconds, rewriting existing application from Angular.js to React, adding features like keyboard navigations and shortcuts to main



🙎 Mumbai, India



+91-9930185246



vadsaria.ak@gmail.com



ÎM /aquib-vadsaria



(agumus)

SKILLS

Proficient: HTML5, CSS3, IS, React.js, Redux, Rx.js, Typescript, GIT, ES6, JSON, AJAX.

Intermediate: Node.js, Express.js, Socket.io, MongoDB, Jest, Mocha, JQuery, Electron, Webpack, Rollup.js, Angular, JS & React profiling, TDD.

Basic: Java, Python, Machine Learning, UNIX, AWS web services, shell scripting, MySQL, Agile methodologies

EDUCATION

B.E in Electronics and Telecommunication - Mumbai University

CERTIFICATION & COURSES

Machine Learning, Stanford University - 2017

System X Certified Engineer - 2013

LANGUAGES

English (fluent)

Hindi (native)

Gujarati(Basic)

- Optimized developer experience by transpiling only changed files using gulp task.
- Mentored Junior developers for React and JS patterns, writing readable code.
- Developed testing framework to test web services and REST API.

Technology stack: React, Flux, ES6, Typescript, GIT, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Gulp, Mocha, Angular.js, AWS.

IBM India Pvt. Ltd. – System Support Representative

JULY 2012 - AUGUST 2015

- Implemented Enterprise servers, SAN storages and network switches
- Configured servers, hardware and OS level hardening and clustering to be used as High Availability SAP Database server.
- Supported L2 level of breakdown issues and co-ordinated escalated issues with Product Engineer for new firmware updates or hardware fixes.
- Developed Dashboard and admin page for server logging system using HTML5, CSS3, JS and JQuery.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

RSyncBackup

Early stage Desktop application for taking files backup. Main objective was to have an UI interface for using rsync commands in Windows WSL.

Economic Planning

Leaded the front end team of volunteers and developed application for NGO which is used to plan economies, funding and to track consultation reviews of various families.

Android ROM Testing

Testing and raising bugs/defects on XDA Developers for nightly build of custom android ROM targeted for mobile devices like HTC HD2, Samsung S3, One Plus one.

HOBBIES

Reading Tech blogs

Music

Watching TV Shows

CURRENTLY LEARNING

Machine Learning

Python

Vue.js

GraphQL